<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kathmandu Interim report</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>/kathmandu/</link>
    <atom:link href="/kathmandu/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 05:37:27 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 05:37:27 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.2.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Business outlook</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This section presents the findings related to the future outlook of the industry. It explores the expectation of the owners pertaining to the length of disruptions, the impact on their income, and the challenges the businesses are facing. The survey finds that the majority of the business owners expect the disruptions to last for around a year. More than twenty percent of the businesses expect to have no or little income compared to 2019. Similarly, challenges related to gaining back trust and managing finances surface prominently among the business owners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu/assets/img/charts/BizDisruptionLastDist.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Majority of the business owners, around sixty five percent, expected the disruption to last less than a year. Only around one in ten business owners expected the disruption to last for more than two years. It is evident that during the time of the survey, the majority of the business owners did not envision the second wave of COVID-19 to impact their business. These estimates could likely change given the second wave that has hit Nepal and the ensuing government imposed lockdown and travel restrictions, including suspension of international flights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu/assets/img/charts/BizExpectedRevenueChangeDist.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, the majority of the business owners expect their revenues to be affected during 2021, which aligns with their expectation of how long the impact of COVID-19 will last. Around two in five business owners expect to earn no or negligible income in 2021. Only around one in twenty, business owners expect the income level to be at similar or a higher level than that of 2019.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These numbers suggest that even without the projection of impact due to the second wave, the business owners had a bleak outlook for their earnings. The second wave would likely exacerbate the situation even further.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu/assets/img/charts/BizBiggestDifficultiesMultiples.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Which of the following are likely to be your biggest difficulties in 2021?&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Respondents could select more than one answer for this question. Each pie chart represents the percentage of respondents that choose a given option.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest challenges for the business owners pertain to reviving the tourists’ confidence and managing finances. Around two thirds of the business owners expect that winning the confidence of tourists and guests is a major challenge. It could be that the business owners expect travelers to bide their time before making travel plans. Factors such as the rate of vaccination in a country, the availability of flights, the overall economic outlook in the origin countries/ places play a role in determining the flow of tourists. Similarly, the behavioral change required, shifting from a largely sedentary lockdown lifestyle to a more active travel lifestyle could also be another factor that could determine when travels resume. More research in this topic will likely reveal nuanced insights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu/assets/img/charts/BizBiggestDifficultiesRnk1Dist.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second and third biggest difficulties of the business owners pertain to managing finances. Around sixty percent of the respondents are concerned about a shortage of cash flow to sustain their operations. The shortage of access to loans and additional funds compounds this shortage of cash. Two in five business owners also mention that accessing additional resources is a major concern for them. Similarly, understanding the demands of source markets and ensuring safety for tourists and workforce are also other major concerns for the business owners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu/assets/img/charts/BizBiggestSupportDist.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Majority of the business owners have expectations from the government to take a central role supporting their businesses. Around one in two business owners expect government agencies such as ministries, Department of Tourism, and the Tourism Board, among other departments, to provide support. Our preliminary research suggests that they pertain to eco-system level support such as ease of travel for tourists (limited or no quarantine period for travelers with negative PCR tests), tax-subsidies for businesses, utility subsidies, and access to emergency funds and grants. Around thirteen percent of the business owners also expect support from financial institutions and unions and associations. The support from the financial institutions would be instrumental in helping sustain the operations and that from the associations would be important in voicing the concerns of businesses to the government entities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The role of informal networks such as friends and family is also important to sustain the businesses. More than one in ten business owners expect their family and friends to support their ventures. This number seems low compared to the informal discussions and research the C2M2 team conducted. This could be because of multiple reasons. The owners could have exhausted support from informal sources in early months of impact, thus leaving them with little space to return to the same sources for support. It could also be that the owners have limited social capital to rely on. Further research on this topic would yield more nuanced insights for the policymakers as to the role of informal networks and institutions in supporting businesses during the times of COVID.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src='/kathmandu/assets/img/charts/BizExpectedWorkforceChangeDist.png'/&gt;&lt;figcaption class='maincolumn-figure'&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt; --&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 09 May 2021 05:46:04 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/kathmandu/articles/21/business-outlook</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/kathmandu/articles/21/business-outlook</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>css</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Business needs</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;With 77% of businesses being closed at least once during the pandemic, majority of them reporting a revenue of almost zero in 2020, and most of the business houses falling into the COVID-induced debt for their survival, this section lists down these business’ expected interventions which they think will help them out of this predicaments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu/assets/img/charts/NextSixMonthsBusinessProblemsMultiples.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Within the next six months, which of the following problems will your business face?&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Respondents could select more than one answer for this question. Each pie chart represents the percentage of respondents that choose a given option.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;pre-existing-burdens-become-even-heavier&quot;&gt;PRE-EXISTING BURDENS BECOME EVEN HEAVIER&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two-thirds of the businesses reported that they will face difficulties in paying back their existing loans. These 58 businesses, when asked to choose the type of assistance that will help them pay off their debts, 59% reported they prefer reduced interest loans whereas 41% prefer to have their loan payback periods extended instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu/assets/img/charts/MostHelpfulLoanPaybackDist.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;customers-will-be-king---more-than-ever-before&quot;&gt;CUSTOMERS WILL BE KING - MORE THAN EVER BEFORE&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two-thirds of the businesses also reported that acquiring enough customers to survive will be a major issue for the next six months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;40% of such businesses believe that they do not have enough resources to understand the needs and aspirations of the source markets that their businesses cater to. 34% of businesses are looking for direct business generation programs from different sources such as trade fairs, direct advertisements, etc. The remaining 26% opine that upgrading their digital marketing skills will be the key to survive in the coming months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu/assets/img/charts/PreferredOutreachAssistanceDist.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;taxes&quot;&gt;TAXES&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;55% of businesses also reported that paying taxes will be a big burden for them by the next six months. Their preferred ways of tax repayments are&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu/assets/img/charts/PreferredTaxAssistanceDist.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;42% of businesses prefer the amount of taxes to be reduced, whereas 29% of businesses think that direct VAT return is the best intervention for them. Businesses are not very keen on deferring taxes or just exemption of fine on taxes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;source&quot;&gt;SOURCE&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Incidentally, almost three-fourths of the respondents prefer to receive financial assistance from the government. Only 22% businesses prefer to acquire additional loans from banks, whereas only 6% of businesses will be looking to acquire such loans from existing shareholders or new shareholders (through acquisitions, mergers or consolidations with other businesses)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu/assets/img/charts/PreferredSourceFinAssistanceDist.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the businesses that will be seeking additional funds, two-thirds of them prefer longer-term subsidized loans whereas only one-third prefer short-term loans without collateral.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu/assets/img/charts/MostHelpfulFundsAssistanceDist.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;labor&quot;&gt;LABOR&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;28% of businesses have reported that they anticipate to face labor-related issues within the next six months. However, only 8% of these businesses anticipate that access to skilled/semi-skilled workers will be their major issue. 44% said that a government policy to not increase minimum wage rates for their next some time will be most helpful to them. On the other hand, a sizable proportion of businesses (48%) see vaccinating their employees as a major concern for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu/assets/img/charts/PreferredLaborAssistanceDist.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;policy-support&quot;&gt;POLICY SUPPORT&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We asked all the respondents what types of government policies would be helpful for their businesses. Each business could choose upto three such policies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu/assets/img/charts/PolicySupportMultiples.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;What kind of policy level support from the government would be most helpful to your business?&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Respondents could select more than one answer for this question. Each pie chart represents the percentage of respondents that choose a given option.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two-thirds of the respondents have reported ‘establishment of a tourism protection fund’ will help them better deal with this type of crisis. Half the respondents are seeking for better government policies around financial assistance. Only 13% marked ‘establishment of job retention fund’ as one of their top three choices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;43% of respondents believe that the port of entries into Nepal should be more tightly regulated. Interestingly, only 8% of respondents think that a Training of Trainers programs on Health and Hygiene Sanitation should be one of their top three choices among the given list. An even lower (6%) seek government assistance in skill enhancement programs for their human resources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A quarter of the respondents have asked the government to establish an authentic source of information regarding COVID-related information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somehow, only 24% of respondents think that a government verification system of labelling businesses as safe and unsafe (such as green, yellow and red stickers) is useful to them.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 09 May 2021 05:46:04 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/kathmandu/articles/21/business-needs</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/kathmandu/articles/21/business-needs</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>css</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Business actions</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-hit-them-hard-the-common-detriments&quot;&gt;WHAT HIT THEM HARD: THE COMMON DETRIMENTS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We asked each business which factors adversely affected them during the pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu/assets/img/charts/BizMostDamagingFactorsMultiples.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Which of the following factors affected your business operations during the pandemic?&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Respondents could select more than one answer for this question. Each pie chart represents the percentage of respondents that choose a given option.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Almost 50% of respondents cited the second-order effects of the government-imposed lockdown, such as lack of mobility and inaccessibility of the required services, as one of the prominent reasons that their business suffered. The most common cause was the reduced volume of business, which most probably is also because of the lockdown that severely restricted the movement of people (customers) for these businesses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another prominent detriment was the lack of financial resources required to keep these businesses running smoothly. It seems that when the lockdown was imposed, the number of COVID cases were also slowly on the rise, as reported by 33% of the respondents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, it hints that the government imposed the lockdown before other effects of COVID, such as shortage of human resources, COVID-affected employees, etc. could manifest and affect these businesses. Had the situation been worse when the lockdown had been first implemented, one would suspect these percentages to be higher than 13% and 9%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-hit-them-hard-the-major-culprits&quot;&gt;WHAT HIT THEM HARD: THE MAJOR CULPRITS&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each respondent was also asked to choose three major factors that affected their business operations. Again, almost 4 out of every 10 businesses reported that the reduced volume of business hit them the hardest. The second-most prominent factor was the lack of adequate financial resources, which could be a direct result of the reduced volume of business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu/assets/img/charts/BizMostDamagingFactorsRnk1Dist.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-actions-they-took&quot;&gt;WHAT ACTIONS THEY TOOK&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section explains the different actions that these businesses took along the various dimensions as a response to the COVID-induced difficulties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;workforce&quot;&gt;WORKFORCE&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Asking workers to take unpaid leave or laying off these workers seemed to be the most common practice, unfortunately. With reduced or zero revenues as reported by most businesses in 2020, these steps were probably the preferred method of slashing fixed costs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu/assets/img/charts/BizWorkforceActionsMultiples.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Which of the following workforce related actions did your business take due to the pandemic?&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Respondents could select more than one answer for this question. Each pie chart represents the percentage of respondents that choose a given option.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other milder interventions like reducing working hours, or decreasing employee benefits, or introducing rotational employment seemed to be less popular actions among the businesses. However, only 22% of respondents reported actually asking their workers to work for reduced pay. 16% asked workers to take paid leave. Perhaps these are indicators of reduced or no business, and hence the businesses saw not much sense in retaining these workers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;borrowing&quot;&gt;Borrowing&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Owing to the lack of financial resources, half of the businesses reported they tried to take loans. It is inconclusive, however, that the remaining half either did not take trying loans even if they needed it, or they did not need it at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu/assets/img/charts/LoanNoLoanSplit.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only 9% of respondents said that they were able to acquire a loan easily. As many as twice that number did take a loan but only by going through significantly difficult processes. 26% said they tried to take loans but they could not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu/assets/img/charts/BizLoanActionsMultiples.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Which of the following loan related impacts did your business have to face due to the pandemic?&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Respondents could select more than one answer for this question. Each pie chart represents the percentage of respondents that choose a given option.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;xxxxxxx% of businesses had reported that they already have existing loans. yyyyyy% of those said that they faced difficulties in paying them back during the pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;asset-liquidity&quot;&gt;Asset liquidity&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu/assets/img/charts/TrySellNoTrySellSplit.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As high as 62% of businesses tried to sell or rent out some of their assets during this pandemic. 34% were able to sell some assets, and 10% successfully rented out their assets. 26% of those who wanted to sell their assets failed to find willing buyers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu/assets/img/charts/BizAssetActionsMultiples.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Which of the following asset related impacts did your business have to face due to the pandemic?&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Respondents could select more than one answer for this question. Each pie chart represents the percentage of respondents that choose a given option.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;investments-and-costs&quot;&gt;Investments and costs&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Government of Nepal had declared 2020 as the Visit Nepal year. The nation had ambitious goals of bringing in over 1.5 million tourists. The Visit Nepal 2020 got cancelled in March, right before the first lockdown.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had asked if the businesses had made significant investments targeting Visit Nepal 2020. 43% of businesses said they did. 32% said that they cancelled or postponed their investment plans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu/assets/img/charts/VnInvestmentSplit.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;80% of businesses reported that they could not cover their operating costs (electricity, rent, etc.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu/assets/img/charts/BizCostActionsMultiples.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Which of the following cost related impacts did your business have to face due to the pandemic?&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Respondents could select more than one answer for this question. Each pie chart represents the percentage of respondents that choose a given option.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;location-location-location&quot;&gt;Location, location, location&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Migration of people is expected during this type of crisis. We also wanted to know if this is true for the businesses. Almost 4 out of 10 businesses actually tried to change their office/business to a different location. 13% of respondents did actually move to a different location. 26% tried to migrate but could not; while a quarter of our respondents had to close one or more of their offices/branches completely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu/assets/img/charts/TryMoveNoTryMoveSplit.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu/assets/img/charts/BizLocationActionsMultiples.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Which of the following location related impacts did your business have to face due to the pandemic?&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Respondents could select more than one answer for this question. Each pie chart represents the percentage of respondents that choose a given option.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;operations&quot;&gt;OPERATIONS&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu/assets/img/charts/ShutNoShutSplit.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;equity-and-ownership&quot;&gt;EQUITY AND ownership&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;staying-afloat-by-selling-stakes&quot;&gt;Staying afloat by selling stakes&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;35% of business also resorted to selling a part of its ownership stakes in order to survive. Only 9% succeeded, however. The remaining 26% could not find willing buyers. It is not surprising that not many are&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu/assets/img/charts/TrySellEquityOrNotSplit.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu/assets/img/charts/BizEquityActionsMultiples.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Which of the following equity related impacts did your business have to face due to the pandemic?&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Respondents could select more than one answer for this question. Each pie chart represents the percentage of respondents that choose a given option.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;selling-the-entire-business&quot;&gt;Selling the entire business&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a dismal looking picture, a quarter of our respondents reported that they tried to sell their entire business because of the pandemic - read some resembling stories here. However, only 1% could sell their business, whereas 23% failed to find a willing buyer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu/assets/img/charts/TrySellBizOrNotSplit.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu/assets/img/charts/BizSellActionsMultiples.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Which of the following ownership related impacts did your business have to face due to the pandemic?&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Respondents could select more than one answer for this question. Each pie chart represents the percentage of respondents that choose a given option.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu/assets/img/charts/EquityOwnSplit.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 09 May 2021 05:42:04 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/kathmandu/articles/21/business-actions</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/kathmandu/articles/21/business-actions</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>css</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Business impacts</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;newthought&quot;&gt;Tourism business have suffered enormously during the pandemic.&lt;/span&gt; 
The following section gives a peek into the impacts of the COVID-19 on the tourism businesses of Kathmandu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-huge-loss&quot;&gt;A HUGE LOSS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Except for a negligible fraction, almost all the tourism businesses shut down during the pandemic. A big chunk (77%) closed temporarily, significantly 17% may never open again. The closure, in turn, has cascading effects on the employment, income, and livelihoods of the people associated with it apart from the loss of years of experience gained by those people in the field of Nepali tourism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu/assets/img/charts/BizOperationsShutDownSplit.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Among the businesses that were temporarily shut down, more than half were shut for more than a year. Only a negligible percentage were shut for less than 3 months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu/assets/img/charts/BizOperationsTempShutDownDurationSplit.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;dropping-revenues-and-negative-savings&quot;&gt;Dropping Revenues and negative savings&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the majority of the businesses, there was no revenue during the pandemic. Even for the rest, revenues had decreased drastically, as shown in the graph below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu/assets/img/charts/BizRevenueChangeDist.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A part of this lack of revenue would definitely have translated to 87% of the businesses ending up with negative savings i.e. having to borrow money to sustain themselves. This further added debt i.e. an increase in the future running costs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu/assets/img/charts/BizSavingsChangeDist.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-steep-surge-in-layoffs---workforces-emptying-to-zero&quot;&gt;A steep surge in layoffs - workforces emptying to zero&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consequently, the overall workforce size took a major hit. 37% of the workforce emptied to zero, three fourth of the workforce were laid off in 28% of the businesses, half in 14%, and one-fourth in 9%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu/assets/img/charts/BizWorkforceChangeDist.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 09 May 2021 05:42:04 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/kathmandu/articles/21/business-impacts</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/kathmandu/articles/21/business-impacts</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>css</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Workforce outlook</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This section explores the expectations of the workers regarding the length of impact, the challenges for recovery, and the impact on employment status in future. While the business owners expected the impact to last for short term (less than a year), majority of the workers expect the impact to last for short (less than a year) and medium term (upto two years). The workers and the business owners align in their views regarding the challenges. They mention that gaining back the trust of the tourists along with the financial issues are the major obstacles for recovery. Finally, the majority of the workers are uncertain as to when the situation would get back to normal. This uncertainty has taken both financial and mental toll on the workers- as evident in the other sections of the survey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu/assets/img/charts/HowLongEconRecoveryDist.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An overwhelming majority of the workers expect the impact of the pandemic to last for mid and long term. Around one in three workers expect their livelihood to be impacted for anywhere between six months to a year. Similarly another third expect the impact to last between one and two years. More than a quarter of the workforce expect the impact to last for a long-term, i.e. beyond a duration of two years.  The numbers suggest that even without a second wave, the impact on workers’ livelihood is already significant. The second wave would likely worsen the impact on the workers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the workers’ perspective, ensuring health, hygiene, and safety standards is one of the major challenges for the recovery of the sector. More than eight in ten workers identified this as a major challenge. As a service sector, which requires close interaction with the clients, it is a challenge to ensure the safety of both the personnel and the visitors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu/assets/img/charts/WrkerBiggestChallengesMultiple.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Which of the following are some challenges in the recovery of your tourism sector?&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Respondents could select more than one answer for this question. Each pie chart represents the percentage of respondents that choose a given option.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, the current reduction in the number of tourists and the ensuing challenge to gain the trust back were also cited as major challenges. More than two third of the workers responded that reduction in the number of tourists is a concern. As the inflow of tourists is instrumental to keep the businesses afloat, reduction in the number makes it difficult for business operations. As a result, the workers are impacted directly when the operations are impacted. This is only one side of the story though. Gaining the trust of the tourists- that the travel destination is safe or that it is safe to travel in general- is also a major challenge. The business owners also highlight similar concerns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Financial issues that have hit the industry is another challenge the workers highlighted. Almost two-thirds of the workers mention this as a matter of concern. The finances are closely linked to the flow of tourists, including the perception regarding safety, and the ability to gain the trust back. The financial concerns do not just pertain to the business operations but also to the daily livelihood of the workers. The workers, who are facing financial challenges, have to resort to alternatives- including permanent switch of sectors. This would impact the availability of the workforce- both in the current state and once when the travel resumes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not surprisingly, when asked to rank the overall challenges, the workers ranked reduction in tourists, ensuring health, hygiene, and safety standards, and financial challenges as the three major challenges the industry faces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu/assets/img/charts/WrkerBiggestChallengesRnk1Dist.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The survey suggests that the uncertainty regarding return to “normalcy” will linger. Three in five workers are uncertain as to when their employment status is likely to return to normal. This uncertainty could be influenced by a number of factors such as perception of the impact due to COVID. Workers who were unemployed during the majority of 2020 might be more pessimistic than those who kept their employment in some form. Said that there is also some optimism in the workers’ group. Similarly, around thirty percent expect their employment status to return to normal within a year. However, it is yet to be assessed if this optimism would persist in the face of the second wave.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu/assets/img/charts/HowLongEmplymntRecoveryDist.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 08 May 2021 05:46:04 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/kathmandu/articles/21/workforce-outlook</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/kathmandu/articles/21/workforce-outlook</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>css</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Workforce needs</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Owing to the high percentages of workers who’ve lost their jobs and are yet to find employment, it is not surprising that the top three sought help are discounted borrowings, opportunities of employment, and grants – as reported by 25.2%, 17.5% and 16.5% of the respondents respectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu/assets/img/charts/NeedsRnk1Dist.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;Respondents were presented with the options shown on the chart, and ask to select all that apply. They were then asked to pick the most important from all of their personal choices. &lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;Graph to the left shows the distribution what respondents considered most important.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems that the other types of help like repaying their existing loans, or developing new skills, reduction of taxes, etc. are almost afterthoughts in their current situations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;financial-needs&quot;&gt;FINANCIAL NEEDS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two-thirds of them have reported that borrowings (i.e. additional funds) at discounted rates of interests will be very helpful. 54% are also looking for grants, while 38% are looking for discounted interest rates on their existing loans. A quarter of the respondents have also cited extension or deferral of loan payments will be helpful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu/assets/img/charts/FinancialNeedsMultiple.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Which of the following forms of financial support will help you minimize the effects of the pandemic?&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Respondents could select more than one answer for this question. Each pie chart represents the percentage of respondents that choose a given option.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;health-related-needs&quot;&gt;HEALTH RELATED NEEDS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu/assets/img/charts/HealthNeedsMultiple.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Which of the following forms of health related support will help you minimize the effects of the pandemic?&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Respondents could select more than one answer for this question. Each pie chart represents the percentage of respondents that choose a given option.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although, almost all the respondents have reported at least one health and psychosocial impact of this pandemic on their well-being, less than 3 out of 10 are actively seeking medical help for the same. Could social stigma around those seeking mental health counseling could be a cause?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;professional-needs&quot;&gt;PROFESSIONAL NEEDS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu/assets/img/charts/ProfessionalNeedsMultiple.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Which of the following forms of professional development support will help you minimize the effects of the pandemic?&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Respondents could select more than one answer for this question. Each pie chart represents the percentage of respondents that choose a given option.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;47% of respondents have reported that employment is one of the top three helps that they are seeking at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;54% are also looking for some sort of professional development training or retraining. Most of these people are involved in &lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;__ sub-sector within tourism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;45% of the respondents, on the other hand, are actively looking to develop new skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, more than 50% of tourism workers that we surveyed are asking for social security benefits. These people are/were involved in _____ sub-sector within the tourism sector.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2021 05:46:04 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/kathmandu/articles/21/workforce-needs</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/kathmandu/articles/21/workforce-needs</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>css</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Workforce impact </title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Insights shown in this page have been derived from the responses of 169 participants who took part in the C2M2 Workforce survey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;economic-effects&quot;&gt;Economic effects&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this section, we look at the impact that the COVID-19 pandemic has had on the Nepali tourism workforce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;still-searching&quot;&gt;STILL SEARCHING&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More than 80% of our respondents reported losing their job at least once during the pandemic. As we can see, a sizable majority (65%) of those who faced unemployent are still without jobs and currently looking for opportunities (see graph below).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu/assets/img/charts/LostOrKeptJobSplit.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu/assets/img/charts/LostJobsSplit.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;Note: The group &amp;#8220;working now&amp;#8221; &lt;strong&gt;also includes&lt;/strong&gt; those who are presently working in sectors other than tourism, but are interested in re-entering the tourism sector.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;!-- ### income &gt; vocation

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src='/kathmandu/assets/img/charts/PresentlyEmployedOccupationSplit.png'/&gt;&lt;figcaption class='maincolumn-figure'&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt; --&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;pay-cuts-the-new-normal&quot;&gt;PAY CUTS: THE New NORMAL?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu/assets/img/charts/PresentlyEmployedUnemployedSplit.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s equally  worrying to learn that nearly 60% of folks who have jobs work at reduced income levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu/assets/img/charts/PresentlyEmployedSalaryCutSplit.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We figured it’s also worth exploring how income losses vary between a) those who managed to retain their employment status throughout the pandemic vs. b) those who lost their jobs once, but managed to find employment again. For reference, here’s what the split looks like graphically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu/assets/img/charts/PresentlyEmployedEmplStatusSplit.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A fifty-fifty split. Now, on to income losses. It appears pay cuts are more common for employees who value job security. Only 3% who remained employed all through the pandemic have managed to retain their pre-pandemic incomes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu/assets/img/charts/StayedEmployedSplit.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;#### A Year of reduced income
63% of our workers who are presently employed have reported not seeing their earnings return to pre-pandemic levels for more than a year now (see graph below).

&amp;lt;figure&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src='/kathmandu/assets/img/charts/LastDateFullSalaryDistPresentlyEmployed.png'/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;figcaption class='maincolumn-figure'&amp;gt;Note: This chart contains responses from &amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;only those respondents who are presently employed&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;. &amp;lt;br /&amp;gt; &amp;lt;br /&amp;gt; To be intepreted as: 63% of workers who are presently employed have not seen their salaries return to pre-pandemic levels since &amp;amp;#8220;Before March 2020&amp;amp;#8221;&amp;lt;/figcaption&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/figure&amp;gt; 
It appears the situation is going to get even more difficult with the second wave approaching.


### Dealing with the financial impact

It's clear many workers aren't earning at the levels they previously used to. At this point, let's try and understand the different financial strategies used by our respondents in dealing with this economic shock brought forth by the crisis.


#### SAVINGS: REDUCED to NEAR-zero

The indefinite nature of the pandemic has resulted in a situation where many workers (~ 90%) have seen their savings reduced to zero or near-zero levels. This is alarming, especially with the second-wave looming around the corner. 

&amp;lt;figure&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src='/kathmandu/assets/img/charts/SavingsChangeDist.png'/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;figcaption class='maincolumn-figure'&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/figcaption&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/figure&amp;gt;



#### SELLING ASSETS: Household items are the first to go

Around one in every four respondents had to do away with some of their personal or household assets. Thankfully, only a few of our respondents have had to sell professional equipment (7%) or land and property (7%) so far.

&amp;lt;figure&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src='/kathmandu/assets/img/charts/SoldStuffMultiples.png'/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;figcaption class='maincolumn-figure'&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/figcaption&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/figure&amp;gt;


#### BORROWING MONEY: Friends and family to the rescue

Our in-person interviews revealed that workers in the tourism sector shy away from borrowing though financial institutions. The reason is that they lack property, real-estate, or other assets that can be provided as collateral. And indeed, our survey results also seem to corroborate with this idea, with more than three-fifths (64%) of our srespondents admit to borrowing exclusively from friends and family. 

&amp;lt;figure&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src='/kathmandu/assets/img/charts/BorrowingSplit.png'/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;figcaption class='maincolumn-figure'&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/figcaption&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/figure&amp;gt;

The situation is worsened by the fact that at present, nearly all (93%) of our respondents report that they are in some form of debt.
&amp;lt;figure&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img src='/kathmandu/assets/img/charts/LoanExposure.png'/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;figcaption class='maincolumn-figure'&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/figcaption&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/figure&amp;gt;

Unfortunately, being in debt -- as our data shows -- is a very real possibility in the &quot;new normal&quot;.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-next-six-months&quot;&gt;the next six months&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unsurprisingly – and rather unfortunately – immediate priorities of workers in the tourism industry seem to echo those of our ancestors in the stone age: food and shelter. The COVID-19 pandemic has really take a big economic toll on individuals. With reduced savings, few options for borrowing, and increasing debt, the situation of the Nepalese tourism labour force seems very fragile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu/assets/img/charts/NextSixMonthsChallengesRnk1Dist.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu/assets/img/charts/NextSixMonthsChallengesMultiples.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Which of the following are some challenges you are likely to face in the next 6 months?&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Respondents could select more than one answer for this question. Each pie chart represents the percentage of respondents that choose a given option.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;skills-loss&quot;&gt;Skills loss&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;!-- &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src='/kathmandu/assets/img/charts/MovementSplit.png'/&gt;&lt;figcaption class='maincolumn-figure'&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src='/kathmandu/assets/img/charts/TempPermMigrationSplit.png'/&gt;&lt;figcaption class='maincolumn-figure'&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src='/kathmandu/assets/img/charts/TempEmployedSplit.png'/&gt;&lt;figcaption class='maincolumn-figure'&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src='/kathmandu/assets/img/charts/PermEmployedSplit.png'/&gt;&lt;figcaption class='maincolumn-figure'&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 --&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu/assets/img/charts/PresentlyEmployedUnemployedSplit.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu/assets/img/charts/PresentlyEmployedJobSwitchSplit.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;!-- ## Effects on workers families



&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src='/kathmandu/assets/img/charts/FamilyMoveNoMoveSplit.png'/&gt;&lt;figcaption class='maincolumn-figure'&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src='/kathmandu/assets/img/charts/TemporaryPermanentMovementSplit.png'/&gt;&lt;figcaption class='maincolumn-figure'&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;




&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src='/kathmandu/assets/img/charts/WitdhrawEducationDist.png'/&gt;&lt;figcaption class='maincolumn-figure'&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src='/kathmandu/assets/img/charts/WitdhrawHealthServiceDist.png'/&gt;&lt;figcaption class='maincolumn-figure'&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt; --&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;psychosocial-effects&quot;&gt;Psychosocial effects&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu/assets/img/charts/PsychologicallyAffectedDist.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the COVID-19 pandemic sweeps across the world, people globally have reported an increase in issues pertaining to their mental health and psychosocial wellbeing. The same has been seen among the tourism workers&lt;label for=&quot;Two&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle sidenote-number&quot;&gt;&lt;/label&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;Two&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot; /&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sidenote&quot;&gt;“My energy to work more, take tourism to new heights has died. I used to donate 5% of my income to charity and now I dont feel like working anymore. Rather, dont even feel like talking.” &lt;/span&gt;. Almost all the workers have reported some form of effects on their mental health and psychosocial wellbeing. Our in-person interviews have reflected the same pattern, the causes seem to be the lockdown and dwindling finances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Digging deep, the majority of the workers say that they find it difficult not to think about the situation and feel increased social pressure&lt;label for=&quot;Two&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle sidenote-number&quot;&gt;&lt;/label&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;Two&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot; /&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sidenote&quot;&gt;“The income was great, so the impression in family was good too. Now, the situation has changed.” &lt;/span&gt;. Other effects are an increase in anxiousness, nightmares, and guilt. Such psychological impacts transition into social relationships including one’s relationship with the family members and other people around them. Given that this is a multiple-choice question, such feelings are overlapping among the respondent workers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu/assets/img/charts/PsychosocialEffectsMultiples.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Pychosocial effects of the pandemic&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Respondents could select more than one answer for this question. Each pie chart represents the percentage of respondents that choose a given option.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite almost all the workers reporting some form of effect on their mental health and psychosocial wellbeing, only a fraction reportedly sought medical help&lt;label for=&quot;Two&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle sidenote-number&quot;&gt;&lt;/label&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;Two&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot; /&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sidenote&quot;&gt;Most of the respondents of our in-person interviews reported some form of effects on their mental health. Most, however, opted for informal coping mechanisms including meditation, yoga and music classes. &lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu/assets/img/charts/CounselingDist.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;!-- &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src='/kathmandu/assets/img/charts/NextSixMonthsChallengesMultiples.png'/&gt;&lt;figcaption class='maincolumn-figure'&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt; --&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2021 05:46:04 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/kathmandu/articles/21/workforce-impact</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/kathmandu/articles/21/workforce-impact</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>css</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tufte-style Jekyll blog</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;newthought&quot;&gt;The Tufte Jekyll theme&lt;/span&gt;  is an attempt to create a website design with the look and feel of Edward Tufte’s books and handouts. Tufte’s style is known for its extensive use of sidenotes, tight integration of graphics with text, and well-set typography.&lt;!--more--&gt; The idea for this project is essentially cribbed wholesale from Tufte and R Markdown’s Tufte Handout format&lt;label for=&quot;One&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle sidenote-number&quot;&gt;&lt;/label&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;One&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot; /&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sidenote&quot;&gt;See &lt;a href=&quot;https://tufte-latex.github.io/tufte-latex/&quot;&gt;tufte-latex.github.io/tufte-latex/&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com/tufte_handout_format.html&quot;&gt;rmarkdown.rstudio.com/tufte_handout_format&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/span&gt; This page is an adaptation of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com/examples/tufte-handout.pdf&quot;&gt;Tufte Handout PDF&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;jekyll-customizations&quot;&gt;Jekyll customizations&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Jekyll blog theme is based on the github repository by Edward Tufte &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/edwardtufte/tufte-css&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, which was orginally created by Dave Leipmann, but is now labeled under Edward Tufte’s moniker. I borrowed freely from the Tufte-CSS repo and have transformed many of the typographic and page-structural features into a set of custom Liquid tags that make creating content using this style much easier than writing straight HTML. Essentially, if you know markdown, and mix in a few custom Liquid tags, you can be creating a website with this document style in short order.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The remainder of this sample post is a self-documenting survey of the features of the Tufte-Jekyll theme. I have taken almost all of the sample content from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/edwardtufte/tufte-css&quot;&gt;Tufte-css&lt;/a&gt; repo and embedded it here to illustrate the parity in appearence between the two. The additional verbiage and commentary I have added is to document the custom &lt;em&gt;Liquid&lt;/em&gt; markup tags and other features that are bundled with this theme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-sass-settings-file&quot;&gt;The SASS settings file&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have taken much of the actual &lt;em&gt;Tufte-css&lt;/em&gt; files and modified them as necessary to accomodate the needs inherent in creating a Jekyll theme that has additional writing aids such as the Liquid tags. I have also turned the CSS file into a &lt;a href=&quot;http://sass-lang.com&quot;&gt;SASS&lt;/a&gt; file (the .scss type).  This means that you can alter things like font choices, text color, background color, and underlining style by changing values in this file. When the Jekyll site is built using &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll build&lt;/code&gt; the settings in this file will be compiled into the customized CSS file that the site uses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This file looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;/* This file contains all the constants for colors and font styles */

$body-font:   Lato, ETBembo, Palatino,  &quot;Palatino Linotype&quot;, &quot;Palatino LT STD&quot;, Georgia, serif;
// Note that Gill Sans is the top of the stack and corresponds to what is used in Tufte's books
// However, it is not a free font, so if it is not present on the computer that is viewing the webpage
// The free Google 'Lato' font is used instead. It is similar.
$sans-font: &quot;Lato&quot;, &quot;Gill Sans&quot;, &quot;Gill Sans MT&quot;, &quot;Lato&quot;, Calibri, sans-serif;
$code-font: Consolas, &quot;Liberation Mono&quot;, Menlo, Courier, monospace;
$url-font: &quot;Lucida Console&quot;, &quot;Lucida Sans Typewriter&quot;, Monaco, &quot;Bitstream Vera Sans Mono&quot;, monospace;
$text-color: #111;
$bg-color: #fffff8;
$contrast-color: #a00000;
$border-color: #333333;
$link-style: color; // choices are 'color' or 'underline'. Default is color using $contrast-color set above
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any of these values can be changed in the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_sass/_settings.scss&lt;/code&gt; file before the site is built. The default values are the ones from &lt;em&gt;tufte-css&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;fundamentals&quot;&gt;Fundamentals&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;color&quot;&gt;Color&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although paper handouts obviously have a pure white background, the web is better served by the use of slightly off-white and off-black colors. I picked &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;#fffff8&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;#111111&lt;/code&gt; because they are nearly indistinguishable from their ‘pure’ cousins, but dial down the harsh contrast. Tufte’s books are a study in spare, minimalist design. In his book &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.edwardtufte.com/tufte/books_vdqi&quot;&gt;The Visual Display of Quantitative Information&lt;/a&gt;, he uses a red ink to add some visual punctuation to the buff colored paper and dark ink. In that spirit, links are styled using a similar red color.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;headings&quot;&gt;Headings&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tufte CSS uses &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; for the document title, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; with class &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;code&lt;/code&gt; for the document subtitle, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;h2&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; for section headings, and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; for low-level headings. More specific headings are not encouraged. If you feel the urge to reach for a heading of level 4 or greater, consider redesigning your document:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;[It is] notable that the Feynman lectures (3 volumes) write about all of physics in 1800 pages, using only 2 levels of hierarchical headings: chapters and A-level heads in the text. It also uses the methodology of &lt;em&gt;sentences&lt;/em&gt; which then cumulate sequentially into &lt;em&gt;paragraphs&lt;/em&gt;, rather than the grunts of bullet points. Undergraduate Caltech physics is very complicated material, but it didn’t require an elaborate hierarchy to organize.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.edwardtufte.com/bboard/q-and-a-fetch-msg?msg_id=0000hB&quot;&gt;http://www.edwardtufte.com/bboard/q-and-a-fetch-msg?msg_id=0000hB&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a bonus, this excerpt regarding the use of headings provides an example of using block quotes. Markdown does not have a native &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;cite&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; shorthand, but real html can be sprinkled in with the Markdown text. In the previous example, the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;cite&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; was preceded with a single return after the quotation itself. The previous blockquote was written in Markdown thusly:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-Liquid&quot;&gt;[It is] notable that the Feynman lectures (3 volumes) write about all of physics in 1800 pages, using only 2 levels of hierarchical headings: chapters and A-level heads in the text. It also uses the methodology of *sentences* which then cumulate sequentially into *paragraphs*, rather than the grunts of bullet points. Undergraduate Caltech physics is very complicated material, but it didn’t require an elaborate hierarchy to organize.
&amp;lt;cite&amp;gt;[http://www.edwardtufte.com/bboard/q-and-a-fetch-msg?msg_id=0000hB](http://www.edwardtufte.com/bboard/q-and-a-fetch-msg?msg_id=0000hB)&amp;lt;/cite&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;newthought&quot;&gt;In his later books&lt;/span&gt; &lt;label for=&quot;two&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle sidenote-number&quot;&gt;&lt;/label&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;two&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot; /&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sidenote&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.edwardtufte.com/tufte/books_be&quot;&gt;http://www.edwardtufte.com/tufte/books_be&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/span&gt;, Tufte starts each section with a bit of vertical space, a non-indented paragraph, and sets the first few words of the sentence in small caps. To accomplish this using this style, enclose the sentence fragment you want styled with small caps in a custom Liquid tag called ‘newthought’ like so:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-Liquid&quot;&gt;{% newthought 'In his later books' %}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;text&quot;&gt;Text&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In print, Tufte uses the proprietary Monotype Bembo&lt;label for=&quot;3&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle sidenote-number&quot;&gt;&lt;/label&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;3&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot; /&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sidenote&quot;&gt;See Tufte’s comment in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.edwardtufte.com/bboard/q-and-a-fetch-msg?msg_id=0000Vt&quot;&gt;Tufte book fonts&lt;/a&gt; thread. &lt;/span&gt; font. A similar effect is achieved in digital formats with the now open-source ETBembo, which Tufte-Jekyll supplies with a &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;@font-face&lt;/code&gt; reference to a .ttf file. Thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/daveliepmann/tufte-css/commit/0a810a7d5f4707941c6f9fe99a53ec41f50a5c00&quot;&gt;Linjie Ding&lt;/a&gt;, italicized text uses the ETBembo Italic font instead of mechanically skewing the characters. In case ETBembo somehow doesn’t work, Tufte CSS degrades gracefully to other serif fonts like Palatino and Georgia. Notice that Tufte CSS includes separate font files for &lt;strong&gt;bold&lt;/strong&gt; (strong) and &lt;em&gt;italic&lt;/em&gt; (emphasis), instead of relying on the browser to mechanically transform the text. This is typographic best practice. It’s also really important. Thus concludes my unnecessary use of em and strong for the purpose of example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Code snippets ape GitHub’s font selection using Microsoft’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.microsoft.com/typography/ClearTypeFonts.mspx&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Consolas&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and the sans-serif font uses Tufte’s choice of Gill Sans. Since this is not a free font, and some systems will not have it installed, the free google font &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/fonts/specimen/Lato&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lato&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is designated as a fallback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;epigraphs&quot;&gt;Epigraphs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;epigraph&quot;&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The English language . . . becomes ugly and inaccurate because our thoughts are foolish, but the slovenliness of our language makes it easier for us to have foolish thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;footer&gt;George Orwell, &lt;cite&gt; &quot;Politics and the English Language&quot; &lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/footer&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;epigraph&quot;&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;For a successful technology, reality must take precedence over public relations, for Nature cannot be fooled.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;footer&gt;Richard P. Feynman, &lt;cite&gt; “What Do You Care What Other People Think?” &lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/footer&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to introduce your page or a section of your page with some quotes, use epigraphs. The two examples above show how they are styled. Epigraph elements are modeled after chapter epigraphs in Tufte’s books (particularly &lt;em&gt;Beautiful Evidence&lt;/em&gt;). The &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/edwardtufte/tufte-css&quot;&gt;Tufte-css&lt;/a&gt; gitub repository has detailed instructions on how to achieve this using HTML elements. As an easier alternative, the &lt;em&gt;Tufte-jekyll&lt;/em&gt; theme uses custom &lt;em&gt;Liquid tag&lt;/em&gt; pairs that allow the writer to embed elements such as epigraphs in the middle of the regular Markdown text being edited.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to use an epigraph in a page or section, type this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;{% epigraph 'text of citation' 'author of citation' 'citation source'  %}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;to produce this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;epigraph&quot;&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;I do not paint things, I paint only the differences between things.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;footer&gt;Henri Matisse, &lt;cite&gt;Henri Matisse Dessins: thèmes et variations, 1943&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/footer&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;epigraph&quot;&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt; &quot;How did you go bankrupt?&quot; Two ways. Gradually, then suddenly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;footer&gt;Ernest Hemingway, &lt;cite&gt; &quot;The Sun Also Rises&quot; &lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/footer&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;lists&quot;&gt;Lists&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tufte points out that while lists have valid uses, they tend to promote ineffective writing habits due to their “lack of syntactic and intellectual discipline”. He is particularly critical of hierarchical and bullet-pointed lists. So before reaching for an HTML list element, ask yourself:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Does this list actually have to be represented using an HTML ul or ol element?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Would my idea be better expressed as sentences in paragraphs?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Is my message causally complex enough to warrant a flow diagram instead?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is but a small subset of a proper overview of the topic of lists in communication. A better way to understand Tufte’s thoughts on lists would be to read “The Cognitive Style of PowerPoint: Pitching Out Corrupts Within,” a chapter in Tufte’s book &lt;em&gt;Beautiful Evidence&lt;/em&gt;, excerpted at some length by Tufte himself &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.edwardtufte.com/bboard/q-and-a-fetch-msg?msg_id=0002QF&quot;&gt;on his website&lt;/a&gt;. The whole piece is information-dense and therefore difficult to summarize. He speaks to web design specifically, but in terms of examples and principles rather than as a set of simple do-this, don’t-do-that prescriptions. It is well worth reading in full for that reason alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For these reasons, Tufte CSS encourages caution before reaching for a list element, and by default removes the bullet points from unordered lists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;figures&quot;&gt;Figures&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;margin-figures&quot;&gt;Margin Figures&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;label for=&quot;mf-id-1&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot;&gt;⊕&lt;/label&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;mf-id-1&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot; /&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;marginnote&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;fullwidth&quot; src=&quot;/kathmandu/assets/img/rhino.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;F.J. Cole, “The History of Albrecht Dürer’s Rhinoceros in Zoological Literature,” &lt;em&gt;Science, Medicine, and History: Essays on the Evolution of Scientific Thought and Medical Practice&lt;/em&gt; (London, 1953), ed. E. Ashworth Underwood, 337-356. From page 71 of Edward Tufte’s &lt;em&gt;Visual Explanations&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Images and graphics play an integral role in Tufte’s work. To place figures in the margin, use the custom margin figure liquid tag included in the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_plugins&lt;/code&gt; directory like so:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;{% marginfigure 'mf-id-whatever' 'assets/img/rhino.png' 'F.J. Cole, “The History of Albrecht Dürer’s Rhinoceros in Zoological Literature,” *Science, Medicine, and History: Essays on the Evolution of Scientific Thought and Medical Practice* (London, 1953), ed. E. Ashworth Underwood, 337-356. From page 71 of Edward Tufte’s *Visual Explanations*.'  %}&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that this tag has &lt;em&gt;three&lt;/em&gt; parameters. The first is an arbitrary id. This parameter can be named anything as long as it is unique to this post. The second parameter is the path to the image. And the final parameter is whatever caption you want to be displayed with the figure.  All parameters &lt;em&gt;must&lt;/em&gt; be enclosed in quotes for this simple liquid tag to work!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this example, the &lt;em&gt;Liquid&lt;/em&gt; marginfigure tag was inserted &lt;em&gt;before&lt;/em&gt; the paragraph so that it aligns with the beginning of the paragraph. On small screens, the image will collapse into a small symbol: &lt;span class=&quot;contrast &quot;&gt;⊕&lt;/span&gt; at the location it has been inserted in the manuscript. Clicking on it will open the image.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;full-width-figures&quot;&gt;Full Width Figures&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you need a full-width image or figure, another custom liquid tag is available to use. Oddly enough, it is named ‘fullwidth’, and this markup:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;{% fullwidth 'assets/img/napoleons-march.png' 'Napoleon's March *(Edward Tufte’s English translation)*'  %}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yields this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;fullwidth&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu/assets/img/napoleons-march.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Napoleon’s March &lt;em&gt;(Edward Tufte’s English translation)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;main-column-figures&quot;&gt;Main Column Figures&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides margin and full width figures, you can of course also include figures constrained to the main column. Yes, you guessed it, a custom liquid tag rides to the rescue once again:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;{% maincolumn 'assets/img/export-imports.png' 'From Edward Tufte, *Visual Display of Quantitative Information*, page 92'  %}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;yields this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu/assets/img/exports-imports.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;From Edward Tufte, &lt;em&gt;Visual Display of Quantitative Information&lt;/em&gt;, page 92&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sidenotes-and-margin-notes&quot;&gt;Sidenotes and Margin notes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most prominent and distinctive features of Tufte’s style is the extensive use of sidenotes and margin notes. Perhaps you have noticed their use in this document already. You are very astute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a wide margin to provide ample room for sidenotes and small figures. There exists a slight semantic distinction between &lt;em&gt;sidenotes&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;marginnotes&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;sidenotes&quot;&gt;Sidenotes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sidenotes&lt;label for=&quot;sn-id-whatever&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle sidenote-number&quot;&gt;&lt;/label&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;sn-id-whatever&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot; /&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sidenote&quot;&gt;This is a sidenote and &lt;em&gt;displays a superscript&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/span&gt; display a superscript. The &lt;em&gt;sidenote&lt;/em&gt; Liquid tag contains two components. The first is an identifier allowing the sidenote to be targeted by the twitchy index fingers of mobile device users so that all the yummy sidenote goodness is revealed when the superscript is tapped. The second components is the actual content of the sidenote. Both of these components should be enclosed in single quotes. Note that we are using the CSS ‘counter’ trick to automagically keep track of the number sequence on each page or post. On small screens, the sidenotes disappear and when the superscript is clicked, a side note will open below the content, which can then be closed with a similar click. Here is the markup for the sidenote at the beginning of this paragraph:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;{% sidenote 'sn-id-whatever' 'This is a sidenote and *displays a superscript*'%}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;margin-notes&quot;&gt;Margin notes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Margin notes&lt;label for=&quot;mn-id-whatever&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot;&gt; ⊕&lt;/label&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;mn-id-whatever&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot; /&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;marginnote&quot;&gt;This is a margin note &lt;em&gt;without&lt;/em&gt; a superscript &lt;/span&gt; are similar to sidenotes, but do not display a superscript. The &lt;em&gt;marginnnote&lt;/em&gt; Liquid tags has the same two components as the &lt;em&gt;sidenote&lt;/em&gt; tag. Anything can be placed in a margin note. Well, anything that is an inline element. Block level elements can make the Kramdown parser do strange things. On small screens, the margin notes disappear and this symbol: &lt;span class=&quot;contrast &quot;&gt;⊕&lt;/span&gt; pops up. When clicked, it will open the margin note below the content, which can then be closed with a similar click. The Markdown content has a similar sort of markup as a sidenote, but without a number involved:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;{% marginnote 'mn-id-whatever' 'This is a margin note *without* a superscript' %}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;equations&quot;&gt;Equations&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Markdown parser being used by this Jekyll theme is Kramdown, which contains some built-in &lt;a href=&quot;//www.mathjax.org&quot;&gt;Mathjax&lt;/a&gt; support. Both inline and block-level mathematical figures can be added to the content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For instance, the following inline sequence:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;When \(a \ne 0\), there are two solutions to \(ax^2 + bx + c = 0\)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;is written by enclosing a Mathjax expression within &lt;em&gt;a matching pair of double dollar signs: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;$$&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;When $$ a \ne 0 $$, there are two solutions to $$ ax^2 + bx + c = 0 $$&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, this block-level Mathjax expression:&lt;/p&gt;

\[x = {-b \pm \sqrt{b^2-4ac} \over 2a}\]

&lt;p&gt;is written by enclosing the expression within a pair of &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;$$&lt;/code&gt; with an empty line above and below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;$$ x = {-b \pm \sqrt{b^2-4ac} \over 2a} $$&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can get pretty fancy, for instance, the wave equation’s nabla is no big thing:&lt;/p&gt;

\[\frac{\partial^2 y}{\partial t^2}= c^2\nabla^2u\]

&lt;p&gt;All of the standard &lt;span class=&quot;latex&quot;&gt;L&lt;sup&gt;a&lt;/sup&gt;T&lt;sub&gt;e&lt;/sub&gt;X&lt;/span&gt; equation markup is available to use inside these block tags.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please note that the block-level Mathjax expressions &lt;em&gt;must&lt;/em&gt; be on their own line, separated from content above and below the block by a blank line for the Kramdown parser and the Mathjax javascript to play nicely with one another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Mathjax integration is tricky, and some things such as the inline matrix notation simply do not work well unless allowances are made for using the notation for a small matrix. Bottom line: If you are using this to document mathematics, be super careful to isolate your &lt;span class=&quot;latex&quot;&gt;L&lt;sup&gt;a&lt;/sup&gt;T&lt;sub&gt;e&lt;/sub&gt;X&lt;/span&gt; blocks by blank lines!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tables&quot;&gt;Tables&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tables are, frankly,  a pain in the ass to create. That said, they often are one of the best methods for presenting data. Tabular data are normally presented with right-aligned numbers, left-aligned text, and minimal grid lines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that when writing Jekyll Markdown content, there will often be a need to get some dirt under your fingernails and stoop to writing a little honest-to-god html. Yes, all that hideous &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;table&amp;gt;..&amp;lt;thead&amp;gt;..&amp;lt;th&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; nonsense. &lt;em&gt;And&lt;/em&gt; you must wrap the unholy mess in a &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;div class=&quot;table-wrapper&quot;&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; tag to ensure that the table stays centered in the main content column.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tables are designed with an &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;overflow:scroll&lt;/code&gt; property to create slider bars when the viewport is narrow. This is so that you do not collapse all your beautiful data into a jumble of letters and numbers when you view it on your smartphone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;label for=&quot;table-1-id&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot;&gt; ⊕&lt;/label&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;table-1-id&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot; /&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;marginnote&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Table 1&lt;/em&gt;: A table with default style formatting &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;table-wrapper&quot;&gt;
  &lt;table class=&quot;table-alpha&quot; id=&quot;newspaper-tone&quot;&gt;
    &lt;thead&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;th class=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Content and tone of front-page articles in 94 U.S. newspapers, October and November, 1974&lt;/th&gt;
        &lt;th class=&quot;left&quot;&gt;Number of articles&lt;/th&gt;
        &lt;th&gt;Percent of articles with negative criticism of specific person or policy&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;/thead&gt;
    &lt;tbody&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td class=&quot;text&quot;&gt;Watergate: defendants and prosecutors, Ford’s pardon of Nixon&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;537&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;49%&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td class=&quot;text&quot;&gt;Inflation, high cost of living&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;415&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;28%&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td class=&quot;text&quot;&gt;Government competence: costs, quality, salaries of public employees&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;322&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;30%&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td class=&quot;text&quot;&gt;Confidence in government: power of special interests, trust in political leaders, dishonesty in politics&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;266&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;52%&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td class=&quot;text&quot;&gt;Government power: regulation of business, secrecy, control of CIA and FBI&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;154&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;42%&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td class=&quot;text&quot;&gt;Crime&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;123&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;number r&quot;&gt;30%&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td class=&quot;text&quot;&gt;Race&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;103&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;25%&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td class=&quot;text&quot;&gt;Unemployment&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;100&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;13%&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td class=&quot;text&quot;&gt;Shortages: energy, food&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;68&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;16%&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;/tbody&gt;
  &lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is not the One True Table. Such a style does not exist. One must craft each data table with custom care to the narrative one is telling with that specific data. So take this not as “the table style to use”, but rather as “a table style to start from”. From here, use principles to guide you: avoid chartjunk, optimize the data-ink ratio (“within reason”, as Tufte says), and “mobilize every graphical element, perhaps several times over, to show the data.&lt;label for=&quot;table-id&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle sidenote-number&quot;&gt;&lt;/label&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;table-id&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot; /&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sidenote&quot;&gt;Page 139, &lt;em&gt;The Visual Display of Quantitative Information&lt;/em&gt;, Edward Tufte 2001. &lt;/span&gt; Furthermore, one must know when to reach for more complex data presentation tools, like a custom graphic or a JavaScript charting library.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an example of alternative table styles, academic publications written in &lt;span class=&quot;latex&quot;&gt;L&lt;sup&gt;a&lt;/sup&gt;T&lt;sub&gt;e&lt;/sub&gt;X&lt;/span&gt; often rely on the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;booktabs&lt;/code&gt; package to produce clean, clear tables. Similar results can be achieved in Tufte CSS with the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;booktabs&lt;/code&gt; class, as demonstrated in this table:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;label for=&quot;table-2-id&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot;&gt; ⊕&lt;/label&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;table-2-id&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot; /&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;marginnote&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Table 2&lt;/em&gt;: A table with booktabs style formatting &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;table-wrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;table class=&quot;booktabs&quot;&gt;
          &lt;thead&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;&lt;th colspan=&quot;2&quot; class=&quot;cmid&quot;&gt;Items&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th class=&quot;nocmid&quot;&gt;&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;&lt;th class=&quot;l&quot;&gt;Animal&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th&gt;Description&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th class=&quot;r&quot;&gt;Price ($)&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
          &lt;/thead&gt;
          &lt;tbody&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Gnat&lt;/td&gt;     &lt;td&gt;per gram&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;r&quot;&gt;13.65&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;         &lt;td&gt;each&lt;/td&gt;    &lt;td class=&quot;r&quot;&gt;0.01&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Gnu&lt;/td&gt;      &lt;td&gt;stuffed&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td class=&quot;r&quot;&gt;92.50&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Emu&lt;/td&gt;      &lt;td&gt;stuffed&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td class=&quot;r&quot;&gt;33.33&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Armadillo&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;frozen&lt;/td&gt;  &lt;td class=&quot;r&quot;&gt;8.99&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
          &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The table above was written in HTML as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;div class=&quot;table-wrapper&quot;&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;table class=&quot;booktabs&quot;&amp;gt;
          &amp;lt;thead&amp;gt;
            &amp;lt;tr&amp;gt;&amp;lt;th colspan=&quot;2&quot; class=&quot;cmid&quot;&amp;gt;Items&amp;lt;/th&amp;gt;&amp;lt;th class=&quot;nocmid&quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/th&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/tr&amp;gt;
            &amp;lt;tr&amp;gt;&amp;lt;th class=&quot;l&quot;&amp;gt;Animal&amp;lt;/th&amp;gt;&amp;lt;th&amp;gt;Description&amp;lt;/th class=&quot;r&quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;th&amp;gt;Price ($)&amp;lt;/th&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/tr&amp;gt;
          &amp;lt;/thead&amp;gt;
          &amp;lt;tbody&amp;gt;
            &amp;lt;tr&amp;gt;&amp;lt;td&amp;gt;Gnat&amp;lt;/td&amp;gt;     &amp;lt;td&amp;gt;per gram&amp;lt;/td&amp;gt;&amp;lt;td class=&quot;r&quot;&amp;gt;13.65&amp;lt;/td&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/tr&amp;gt;
            &amp;lt;tr&amp;gt;&amp;lt;td&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/td&amp;gt;         &amp;lt;td&amp;gt;each&amp;lt;/td&amp;gt;    &amp;lt;td class=&quot;r&quot;&amp;gt;0.01&amp;lt;/td&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/tr&amp;gt;
            &amp;lt;tr&amp;gt;&amp;lt;td&amp;gt;Gnu&amp;lt;/td&amp;gt;      &amp;lt;td&amp;gt;stuffed&amp;lt;/td&amp;gt; &amp;lt;td class=&quot;r&quot;&amp;gt;92.50&amp;lt;/td&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/tr&amp;gt;
            &amp;lt;tr&amp;gt;&amp;lt;td&amp;gt;Emu&amp;lt;/td&amp;gt;      &amp;lt;td&amp;gt;stuffed&amp;lt;/td&amp;gt; &amp;lt;td class=&quot;r&quot;&amp;gt;33.33&amp;lt;/td&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/tr&amp;gt;
            &amp;lt;tr&amp;gt;&amp;lt;td&amp;gt;Armadillo&amp;lt;/td&amp;gt;&amp;lt;td&amp;gt;frozen&amp;lt;/td&amp;gt;  &amp;lt;td class=&quot;r&quot;&amp;gt;8.99&amp;lt;/td&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/tr&amp;gt;
          &amp;lt;/tbody&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/table&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;newthought&quot;&gt;I like this style of table,&lt;/span&gt;   so I have made it the default for unstyled tables. This allows use of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://michelf.ca/projects/php-markdown/extra/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Markdown Extra&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; features built into the &lt;a href=&quot;http://kramdown.gettalong.org/parser/kramdown.html&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kramdown&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; parser. Here is a table created using the Markdown Extra table syntax to make a nice table which has the side benefit of being human readable in the raw Markdown file:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;label for=&quot;tableID-3&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot;&gt; ⊕&lt;/label&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;tableID-3&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot; /&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;marginnote&quot;&gt;Table 3: a table created with &lt;em&gt;Markdown Extra&lt;/em&gt; markup using only the default table styling &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt; &lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;mpg&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;cyl&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;disp&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;hp&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;drat&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;wt&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Mazda RX4&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;21&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;160&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;110&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;3.90&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;2.62&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Mazda RX4 Wag&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;21&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;160&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;110&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;3.90&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;2.88&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Datsun 710&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;22.8&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;108&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;93&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;3.85&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;2.32&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Hornet 4 Drive&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;21.4&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;258&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;110&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;3.08&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;3.21&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Hornet Sportabout&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;18.7&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;8&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;360&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;175&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;3.15&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;3.44&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Valiant&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;18.1&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;160&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;105&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;2.76&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;3.46&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using the following Markdown formatting:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;|                 |mpg  | cyl  |  disp  |   hp   |  drat  | wt  |
|:----------------|----:|-----:|-------:|-------:|-------:|----:|
|Mazda RX4        |21   |6     |160     |110     |3.90    |2.62 |
|Mazda RX4 Wag    |21   |6     |160     |110     |3.90    |2.88 |
|Datsun 710       |22.8 |4     |108     |93      |3.85    |2.32 |
etc...
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following is a more simple table, showing the Markdown-style table markup. Remember to label the table with a &lt;em&gt;marginnote&lt;/em&gt; Liquid tag, and you &lt;em&gt;must&lt;/em&gt; separate the label from the table with a single blank line. This markup:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;{% marginnote 'Table-ID4' 'Table 4: a simple table showing left, center, and right alignment of table headings and data'  %}

|**Left** |**Center**|**Right**|
|:--------|:--------:|--------:|
 Aardvarks|         1|$3.50
       Cat|   5      |$4.23
  Dogs    |3         |$5.29
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yields this table:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;label for=&quot;Table-ID4&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot;&gt; ⊕&lt;/label&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;Table-ID4&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot; /&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;marginnote&quot;&gt;Table 4: a simple table showing left, center, and right alignment of table headings and data &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Left&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Center&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Right&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Aardvarks&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;$3.50&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Cat&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;$4.23&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Dogs&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;$5.29&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;code&quot;&gt;Code&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Code samples use a monospace font using the ‘code’ class. The Kramdown parser has the ‘GFM’ option enabled, which stands for ‘Github Flavored Markdown’, and this means that both inline code such as &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;#include &amp;lt;stdio.h&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; and blocks of code can be delimited by surrounding them with 3 backticks:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;(map tufte-style all-the-things)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;is created by the following markup:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;```(map tufte-style all-the-things)```&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get the code highlighted in the language of your choice like so:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-ruby highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;module&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nn&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;class&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;RenderFullWidthTag&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;Liquid&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;::&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;Tag&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;require&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;shellwords&quot;&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;initialize&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tag_name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;text&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tokens&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;super&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;vi&quot;&gt;@text&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;text&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;shellsplit&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;render&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;context&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img class='fullwidth' src='&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vi&quot;&gt;@text&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;'/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt; &quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;span class='marginnote'&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vi&quot;&gt;@text&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;Liquid&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;::&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;Template&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;register_tag&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'fullwidth'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;::&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;RenderFullWidthTag&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enclose the code block in three backticks, followed by a space and then the language name, like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt; &lt;code&gt;``` ruby
    module Jekyll
    blah, blah...
   ```&lt;/code&gt; &lt;/pre&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2020 05:46:04 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/kathmandu/articles/20/tufte-style-jekyll-blog</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/kathmandu/articles/20/tufte-style-jekyll-blog</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>css</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
