<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kathmandu Interim report</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>/kathmandu-interim-report/</link>
    <atom:link href="/kathmandu-interim-report/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 09:54:31 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 09:54:31 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.2.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Business outlook</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This section presents the findings related to the future outlook of the industry. It explores the expectation of the owners pertaining to the length of disruptions, the impact on their income, and the challenges the businesses are facing. The survey finds that the majority of the business owners expect the disruptions to last for around a year. More than twenty percent of the businesses expect to have no or little income compared to 2019. Similarly, challenges related to gaining back trust and managing finances surface prominently among the business owners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu-interim-report/assets/img/charts/BizDisruptionLastDist.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Majority of the business owners, around sixty five percent, expected the disruption to last less than a year. Only around one in ten business owners expected the disruption to last for more than two year. It is evident that during the time of the survey, the majority of the business owners did not envision the second wave of COVID-19 to impact their business. These estimates could likely change given the second wave that has hit Nepal and the ensuing government imposed lockdown and travel restrictions, including suspension of international flights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu-interim-report/assets/img/charts/BizExpectedRevenueChangeDist.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, the majority of the business owners expect their revenues to be affected during 2021, which aligns with their expectation of how long the impact of COVID-19 will last. More than two in five business owners expect to earn no or negligible income in 2021. Only around one in ten, twelve percent, business owners expect the income level to be at similar or a higher level than that of 2019.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These numbers suggest that even without the projection of impact due to the second wave, the business owners had a bleak outlook for their earnings. The second wave would likely exacerbate the situation even further.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu-interim-report/assets/img/charts/BizBiggestDifficultiesMultiples.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Which of the following are likely to be your biggest difficulties in 2021?&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Respondents could select more than one answer for this question. Each pie chart represents the percentage of respondents that choose a given option.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest challenges for the business owners pertain to reviving the tourists’ confidence and managing finances. Around one third of the business owners expect that winning the confidence of tourists and guests is a major challenge. It could be that the business owners expect travelers to bide their time before making travel plans. Factors such as the rate of vaccination in a country, the availability of flights, the overall economic outlook in the origin countries/ places play a role in determining the flow of tourists. Similarly, the behavioral change required, shifting from a largely sedentary lockdown lifestyle to a more active travel lifestyle could also be another factor that could determine when travels resume. More research in this topic will likely reveal nuanced insights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu-interim-report/assets/img/charts/BizBiggestDifficultiesRnk1Dist.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second and third biggest difficulties of the business owners pertain to managing finances. Around one third are concerned about a shortage of cash flow to sustain their operations. The shortage of access to loans and additional funds compounds this shortage of cash. One in five business owners also mention that accessing additional resources is a major concern for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu-interim-report/assets/img/charts/BizBiggestSupportDist.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Majority of the business owners have expectations from the government to take a central role support their businesses. More than one in two business owners expect government agencies such as ministries, Department of Tourism, and the Tourism Board, among other departments, to provide support. Our preliminary research suggests that they pertain to eco-system level support such as ease of travel for tourists (limited or no quarantine period for travelers with negative PCR tests), tax-subsidies for businesses, utility subsidies, and access to emergency funds and grants. Around one in four business owners also expect support from financial institutions and unions and associations. The support from the financial institutions would be instrumental in helping sustain the operations and that from the associations would be important in voicing the concerns of businesses to the government entities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The role of informal networks such as friends and family is also important to sustain the businesses. One in ten business owners expect their family and friends to support their ventures. This number seems low compared to the informal discussions and research the C2M2 team conducted. This could be because of multiple reasons. The owners could have exhausted support from informal sources in early months of impact, thus leaving them with little space to return to the same sources for support. It could also be that the owners have limited social capital to rely on. Further research on this topic would yield more nuanced insights for the policymakers as to the role of informal networks and institutions in supporting businesses during the times of COVID. 
&lt;!-- &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src='/kathmandu-interim-report/assets/img/charts/BizExpectedWorkforceChangeDist.png'/&gt;&lt;figcaption class='maincolumn-figure'&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt; --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 09 May 2021 05:46:04 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/kathmandu-interim-report/articles/21/business-outlook</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/kathmandu-interim-report/articles/21/business-outlook</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>css</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Business needs</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;With 77% of businesses being closed at least once during the pandemic, majority of them reporting a revenue of almost zero in 2020, and most of the business houses falling into the COVID-induced debt for their survival, this section lists down these business’ expected interventions which they think will help them out of this predicaments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu-interim-report/assets/img/charts/NextSixMonthsBusinessProblemsMultiples.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Within the next six months, which of the following problems will your business face?&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Respondents could select more than one answer for this question. Each pie chart represents the percentage of respondents that choose a given option.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;pre-existing-burdens-become-even-heavier&quot;&gt;PRE-EXISTING BURDENS BECOME EVEN HEAVIER&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two-thirds of the businesses reported that they will face difficulties in paying back their existing loans. These 58 businesses, when asked to choose the type of assistance that will help them pay off their debts, 59% reported they prefer reduced interest loans whereas 41% prefer to have their loan payback periods extended instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu-interim-report/assets/img/charts/MostHelpfulLoanPaybackDist.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;customers-will-be-king---more-than-ever-before&quot;&gt;CUSTOMERS WILL BE KING - MORE THAN EVER BEFORE&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two-thirds of the businesses also reported that acquiring enough customers to survive will be a major issue for the next six months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;40% of such businesses believe that they do not have enough resources to understand the needs and aspirations of the source markets that their businesses cater to. 34% of businesses are looking for direct business generation programs from different sources such as trade fairs, direct advertisements, etc. The remaining 26% opine that upgrading their digital marketing skills will be the key to survive in the coming months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu-interim-report/assets/img/charts/PreferredOutreachAssistanceDist.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;taxes&quot;&gt;TAXES&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;55% of businesses also reported that paying taxes will be a big burden for them by the next six months. Their preferred ways of tax repayments are&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu-interim-report/assets/img/charts/PreferredTaxAssistanceDist.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;42% of businesses prefer the amount of taxes to be reduced, whereas 29% of businesses think that direct VAT return is the best intervention for them. Businesses are not very keen on deferring taxes or just exemption of fine on taxes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;source&quot;&gt;SOURCE&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Incidentally, almost three-fourths of the respondents prefer to receive financial assistance from the government. Only 22% businesses prefer to acquire additional loans from banks, whereas only 6% of businesses will be looking to acquire such loans from existing shareholders or new shareholders (through acquisitions, mergers or consolidations with other businesses)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu-interim-report/assets/img/charts/PreferredSourceFinAssistanceDist.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the businesses that will be seeking additional funds, two-thirds of them prefer longer-term subsidized loans whereas only one-third prefer short-term loans without collateral.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu-interim-report/assets/img/charts/MostHelpfulFundsAssistanceDist.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;labor&quot;&gt;LABOR&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;28% of businesses have reported that they anticipate to face labor-related issues within the next six months. However, only 8% of these businesses anticipate that access to skilled/semi-skilled workers will be their major issue. 44% said that a government policy to not increase minimum wage rates for their next some time will be most helpful to them. On the other hand, a sizable proportion of businesses (48%) see vaccinating their employees as a major concern for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu-interim-report/assets/img/charts/PreferredLaborAssistanceDist.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;policy-support&quot;&gt;POLICY SUPPORT&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We asked all the respondents what types of government policies would be helpful for their businesses. Each business could choose upto three such policies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu-interim-report/assets/img/charts/PolicySupportMultiples.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;What kind of policy level support from the government would be most helpful to your business?&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Respondents could select more than one answer for this question. Each pie chart represents the percentage of respondents that choose a given option.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two-thirds of the respondents have reported ‘establishment of a tourism protection fund’ will help them better deal with this type of crisis. Half the respondents are seeking for better government policies around financial assistance. Only 13% marked ‘establishment of job retention fund’ as one of their top three choices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;43% of respondents believe that the port of entries into Nepal should be more tightly regulated. Interestingly, only 8% of respondents think that a Training of Trainers programs on Health and Hygiene Sanitation should be one of their top three choices among the given list. An even lower (6%) seek government assistance in skill enhancement programs for their human resources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A quarter of the respondents have asked the government to establish an authentic source of information regarding COVID-related information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somehow, only 24% of respondents think that a government verification system of labelling businesses as safe and unsafe (such as green, yellow and red stickers) is useful to them.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 09 May 2021 05:46:04 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/kathmandu-interim-report/articles/21/business-needs</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/kathmandu-interim-report/articles/21/business-needs</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>css</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Business actions</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-hurt-businesses&quot;&gt;WHAT HURT BUSINESSES&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu-interim-report/assets/img/charts/BizMostDamagingFactorsMultiples.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Which of the following factors affected your business operations during the pandemic?&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Respondents could select more than one answer for this question. Each pie chart represents the percentage of respondents that choose a given option.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-hurt-the-most&quot;&gt;WHAT HURT THE MOST?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu-interim-report/assets/img/charts/BizMostDamagingFactorsRnk1Dist.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;workforce-actions&quot;&gt;WORKFORCE ACTIONS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu-interim-report/assets/img/charts/BizWorkforceActionsMultiples.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Which of the following workforce related actions did your business take due to the pandemic?&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Respondents could select more than one answer for this question. Each pie chart represents the percentage of respondents that choose a given option.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;borrowing&quot;&gt;Borrowing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu-interim-report/assets/img/charts/LoanNoLoanSplit.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu-interim-report/assets/img/charts/BizLoanActionsMultiples.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Which of the following loan related impacts did your business have to face due to the pandemic?&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Respondents could select more than one answer for this question. Each pie chart represents the percentage of respondents that choose a given option.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;asset-liquidity&quot;&gt;Asset liquidity&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu-interim-report/assets/img/charts/TrySellNoTrySellSplit.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu-interim-report/assets/img/charts/BizAssetActionsMultiples.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Which of the following asset related impacts did your business have to face due to the pandemic?&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Respondents could select more than one answer for this question. Each pie chart represents the percentage of respondents that choose a given option.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;investments-and-costs&quot;&gt;Investments and costs&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu-interim-report/assets/img/charts/VnInvestmentSplit.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu-interim-report/assets/img/charts/BizCostActionsMultiples.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Which of the following cost related impacts did your business have to face due to the pandemic?&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Respondents could select more than one answer for this question. Each pie chart represents the percentage of respondents that choose a given option.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;location-location-location&quot;&gt;Location, location, location&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu-interim-report/assets/img/charts/TryMoveNoTryMoveSplit.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu-interim-report/assets/img/charts/BizLocationActionsMultiples.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Which of the following location related impacts did your business have to face due to the pandemic?&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Respondents could select more than one answer for this question. Each pie chart represents the percentage of respondents that choose a given option.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;operations&quot;&gt;OPERATIONS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu-interim-report/assets/img/charts/ShutNoShutSplit.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;equity-and-ownership&quot;&gt;EQUITY AND ownership&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu-interim-report/assets/img/charts/TrySellBizOrNotSplit.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu-interim-report/assets/img/charts/BizSellActionsMultiples.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Which of the following ownership related impacts did your business have to face due to the pandemic?&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Respondents could select more than one answer for this question. Each pie chart represents the percentage of respondents that choose a given option.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu-interim-report/assets/img/charts/TrySellEquityOrNotSplit.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu-interim-report/assets/img/charts/BizEquityActionsMultiples.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Which of the following equity related impacts did your business have to face due to the pandemic?&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Respondents could select more than one answer for this question. Each pie chart represents the percentage of respondents that choose a given option.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu-interim-report/assets/img/charts/EquityOwnSplit.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 09 May 2021 05:42:04 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/kathmandu-interim-report/articles/21/business-actions</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/kathmandu-interim-report/articles/21/business-actions</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>css</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Business impacts</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The following section gives a peek into the impacts of the COVID-19 on the tourism businesses of Kathmandu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-huge-loss&quot;&gt;A HUGE LOSS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almost 20% of of our respondents reported having to shut down permanently, 77% shut down temporarily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu-interim-report/assets/img/charts/BizOperationsShutDownSplit.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Among the businesses that were temporarily shut down, more than half were shut for more than a year. This number comes up despite the first lockdown was imposed for approximately four months and the second lockdown was imposed for  *months. Only a negligible percentage were shut for less than 3 months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu-interim-report/assets/img/charts/BizOperationsTempShutDownDurationSplit.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;dropping-revenues-and-negative-savings&quot;&gt;Dropping Revenues and negative savings&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the majority of the businesses, there was no revenue during the pandemic. Even for the rest, revenues had decreased drastically, as shown in the graph below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu-interim-report/assets/img/charts/BizRevenueChangeDist.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A part of this lack of revenue would definitely have translated to 87% of the businesses ending up with negative savings i.e. having to borrow money to sustain themselves. This further added debt i.e. an increase in the future running costs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu-interim-report/assets/img/charts/BizSavingsChangeDist.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-steep-surge-in-layoffs---workforces-emptying-to-zero&quot;&gt;A steep surge in layoffs - workforces emptying to zero&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consequently, the overall workforce size took a major hit. 37% of the workforce emptied to zero, three fourth of the workforce were laid off in 28% of the businesses, half in 14%, and one-fourth in 9%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu-interim-report/assets/img/charts/BizWorkforceChangeDist.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 09 May 2021 05:42:04 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/kathmandu-interim-report/articles/21/business-impacts</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/kathmandu-interim-report/articles/21/business-impacts</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>css</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Workforce outlook</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This section explores the expectations of the workers regarding the length of impact, the challenges for recovery, and the impact on employment status in future. While the business owners expected the impact to last for short term (less than a year), majority of the workers expect the impact to last for short (less than a year) and medium term (upto two years). The workers and the business owners align in their views regarding the challenges. They mention that gaining back the trust of the tourists along with the financial issues are the major obstacles for recovery. Finally, the majority of the workers (around sixty percent) are uncertain as to when the situation would get back to normal. This uncertainty has taken both financial and mental toll on the workers- as evident in the other sections of the survey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu-interim-report/assets/img/charts/HowLongEconRecoveryDist.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An overwhelming majority of the workers expect the impact of the pandemic to last for mid and long term. Around one in three workers expect their livelihood to be impacted for anywhere between six months to a year. Similarly another third expect the impact to last between one and two years. More than a quarter of the workforce expect the impact to last for a long-term, i.e. beyond a duration of two years.  The numbers suggest that even without a second wave, the impact on workers’ livelihood is already significant. The second wave would likely worsen the impact on the workers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the workers’ perspective, ensuring health, hygiene, and safety standards is one of the major challenges for the recovery of the sector. More than eight in ten workers identified this as a major challenge. As a service sector, which requires close interaction with the clients, it is a challenge to ensure the safety of both the personnel and the visitors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu-interim-report/assets/img/charts/WrkerBiggestChallengesMultiple.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Which of the following are some challenges in the recovery of your tourism sector?&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Respondents could select more than one answer for this question. Each pie chart represents the percentage of respondents that choose a given option.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, the current reduction in the number of tourists and the ensuing challenge to gain the trust back were also cited as major challenges. More than one third of workers responded that reduction in the number of tourists is a concern. As the inflow of tourists is instrumental to keep the businesses afloat, reduction in the number makes it difficult for business operations. As a result, the workers are impacted directly when the operations are impacted. This is only one side of the story though. Gaining the trust of the tourists- that the travel destination is safe or that it is safe to travel in general- is also a major challenge. The business owners also highlight similar concerns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Financial issues that have hit the industry is another challenge the workers highlighted. Almost two-thirds of the workers mention this as a matter of concern. The finances are closely linked to the flow of tourists, including the perception regarding safety, and the ability to gain the trust back. The financial concerns do not just pertain to the business operations but also to the daily livelihood of the workers. The workers, who are facing financial challenges, have to resort to alternatives- including permanent switch of sectors. This would impact the availability of the workforce- both in the current state and once when the travel resumes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not surprisingly, when asked to rank the overall challenges, the workers ranked reduction in tourists, ensuring health, hygiene, and safety standards, and financial challenges as the three major challenges the industry faces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu-interim-report/assets/img/charts/WrkerBiggestChallengesRnk1Dist.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The survey suggests that the uncertainty regarding return to “normalcy” will linger. More than three in five workers are uncertain as to when their employment status is likely to return to normal. This uncertainty could be influenced by a number of factors such as perception of the impact due to COVID. Workers who were unemployed during the majority of 2020 might be more pessimistic than those who kept their employment in some form. Said that there is also some optimism in the workers’ group. Around three in ten expect their employment status to return to normal within a year. However, it is yet to be assessed if this optimism would persist in the face of the second wave.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu-interim-report/assets/img/charts/HowLongEmplymntRecoveryDist.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 08 May 2021 05:46:04 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/kathmandu-interim-report/articles/21/workforce-outlook</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/kathmandu-interim-report/articles/21/workforce-outlook</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>css</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Workforce needs</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Immediate priorities of the Nepali tourism workforce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu-interim-report/assets/img/charts/NeedsRnk1Dist.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;Respondents were presented with the options shown on the chart, and ask to select all that apply. They were then asked to pick the most important from all of their personal choices. &lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;Graph to the left shows the distribution what respondents considered most important.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;financial-needs&quot;&gt;FINANCIAL NEEDS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu-interim-report/assets/img/charts/FinancialNeedsMultiple.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Which of the following forms of financial support will help you minimize the effects of the pandemic?&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Respondents could select more than one answer for this question. Each pie chart represents the percentage of respondents that choose a given option.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;health-related-needs&quot;&gt;HEALTH RELATED NEEDS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu-interim-report/assets/img/charts/HealthNeedsMultiple.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Which of the following forms of health related support will help you minimize the effects of the pandemic?&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Respondents could select more than one answer for this question. Each pie chart represents the percentage of respondents that choose a given option.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;professional-needs&quot;&gt;PROFESSIONAL NEEDS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu-interim-report/assets/img/charts/ProfessionalNeedsMultiple.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Which of the following forms of professional development support will help you minimize the effects of the pandemic?&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Respondents could select more than one answer for this question. Each pie chart represents the percentage of respondents that choose a given option.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2021 05:46:04 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/kathmandu-interim-report/articles/21/workforce-needs</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/kathmandu-interim-report/articles/21/workforce-needs</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>css</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Workforce impact </title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Insights shown in this page have been derived from the responses of 169 participants who took part in the C2M2 Workforce survey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;economic-effects&quot;&gt;Economic effects&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this section, we look at the impact that the COVID-19 pandemic has had on the Nepali tourism workforce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;still-searching&quot;&gt;STILL SEARCHING&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More than 80% of our respondents reported losing their job at least once during the pandemic. As we can see, a sizable majority (65%) of those who faced unemployent are still without jobs and currently looking for opportunities (see graph below).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu-interim-report/assets/img/charts/LostOrKeptJobSplit.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu-interim-report/assets/img/charts/LostJobsSplit.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;Note: The group &amp;#8220;working now&amp;#8221; &lt;strong&gt;also includes&lt;/strong&gt; those who are presently working in sectors other than tourism, but are interested in re-entering the tourism sector.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;!-- ### income &gt; vocation

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src='/kathmandu-interim-report/assets/img/charts/PresentlyEmployedOccupationSplit.png'/&gt;&lt;figcaption class='maincolumn-figure'&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt; --&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;pay-cuts-the-new-normal&quot;&gt;PAY CUTS: THE New NORMAL?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu-interim-report/assets/img/charts/PresentlyEmployedUnemployedSplit.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s equally  worrying to learn that nearly 60% of folks who have jobs work at reduced income levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu-interim-report/assets/img/charts/PresentlyEmployedSalaryCutSplit.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We figured it’s also worth exploring how income losses vary between a) those who managed to retain their employment status throughout the pandemic vs. b) those who lost their jobs once, but managed to find employment again. For reference, here’s what the split looks like graphically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu-interim-report/assets/img/charts/PresentlyEmployedEmplStatusSplit.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A fifty-fifty split. Now, on to income losses. It appears pay cuts are more common for employees who value job security. Only 3% who remained employed all through the pandemic have managed to retain their pre-pandemic incomes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu-interim-report/assets/img/charts/StayedEmployedSplit.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;a-year-of-reduced-income&quot;&gt;A Year of reduced income&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;63% of our workers who are presently employed have reported not seeing their earnings return to pre-pandemic levels for more than a year now (see graph below).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu-interim-report/assets/img/charts/LastDateFullSalaryDistPresentlyEmployed.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;Note: This chart contains responses from &lt;strong&gt;only those respondents who are presently employed&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt; To be intepreted as: 63% of workers who are presently employed have not seen their salaries return to pre-pandemic levels since &amp;#8220;Before March 2020&amp;#8221;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It appears the situation is going to get even more difficult with the second wave approaching.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;dealing-with-the-financial-impact&quot;&gt;Dealing with the financial impact&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s clear many workers aren’t earning at the levels they previously used to. At this point, let’s try and understand the different financial strategies used by our respondents in dealing with this economic shock brought forth by the crisis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;savings-reduced-to-near-zero&quot;&gt;SAVINGS: REDUCED to NEAR-zero&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The indefinite nature of the pandemic has resulted in a situation where many workers (~ 90%) have seen their savings reduced to zero or near-zero levels. This is alarming, especially with the second-wave looming around the corner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu-interim-report/assets/img/charts/SavingsChangeDist.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;selling-assets-household-items-are-the-first-to-go&quot;&gt;SELLING ASSETS: Household items are the first to go&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Around one in every four respondents had to do away with some of their personal or household assets. Thankfully, only a few of our respondents have had to sell professional equipment (7%) or land and property (7%) so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu-interim-report/assets/img/charts/SoldStuffMultiples.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;borrowing-money-friends-and-family-to-the-rescue&quot;&gt;BORROWING MONEY: Friends and family to the rescue&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our in-person interviews revealed that workers in the tourism sector shy away from borrowing though financial institutions. The reason is that they lack property, real-estate, or other assets that can be provided as collateral. And indeed, our survey results also seem to corroborate with this idea, with more than three-fifths (64%) of our srespondents admit to borrowing exclusively from friends and family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu-interim-report/assets/img/charts/BorrowingSplit.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The situation is worsened by the fact that at present, nearly all (93%) of our respondents report that they are in some form of debt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu-interim-report/assets/img/charts/LoanExposure.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, being in debt – as our data shows – is a very real possibility in the “new normal”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-next-six-months&quot;&gt;the next six months&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unsurprisingly – and rather unfortunately – immediate priorities of workers in the tourism industry seem to echo those of our ancestors in the stone age: food and shelter. The COVID-19 pandemic has really take a big economic toll on individuals. With reduced savings, few options for borrowing, and increasing debt, the situation of the Nepalese tourism labour force seems very fragile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu-interim-report/assets/img/charts/NextSixMonthsChallengesRnk1Dist.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu-interim-report/assets/img/charts/NextSixMonthsChallengesMultiples.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Which of the following are some challenges you are likely to face in the next 6 months?&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Respondents could select more than one answer for this question. Each pie chart represents the percentage of respondents that choose a given option.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;skills-loss&quot;&gt;Skills loss&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;!-- &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src='/kathmandu-interim-report/assets/img/charts/MovementSplit.png'/&gt;&lt;figcaption class='maincolumn-figure'&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src='/kathmandu-interim-report/assets/img/charts/TempPermMigrationSplit.png'/&gt;&lt;figcaption class='maincolumn-figure'&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src='/kathmandu-interim-report/assets/img/charts/TempEmployedSplit.png'/&gt;&lt;figcaption class='maincolumn-figure'&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src='/kathmandu-interim-report/assets/img/charts/PermEmployedSplit.png'/&gt;&lt;figcaption class='maincolumn-figure'&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
 --&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu-interim-report/assets/img/charts/PresentlyEmployedUnemployedSplit.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu-interim-report/assets/img/charts/PresentlyEmployedJobSwitchSplit.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;!-- ## Effects on workers families



&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src='/kathmandu-interim-report/assets/img/charts/FamilyMoveNoMoveSplit.png'/&gt;&lt;figcaption class='maincolumn-figure'&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src='/kathmandu-interim-report/assets/img/charts/TemporaryPermanentMovementSplit.png'/&gt;&lt;figcaption class='maincolumn-figure'&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;




&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src='/kathmandu-interim-report/assets/img/charts/WitdhrawEducationDist.png'/&gt;&lt;figcaption class='maincolumn-figure'&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src='/kathmandu-interim-report/assets/img/charts/WitdhrawHealthServiceDist.png'/&gt;&lt;figcaption class='maincolumn-figure'&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt; --&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;psychosocial-effects&quot;&gt;Psychosocial effects&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu-interim-report/assets/img/charts/PsychologicallyAffectedDist.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu-interim-report/assets/img/charts/PsychosocialEffectsMultiples.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Pychosocial effects of the pandemic&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Respondents could select more than one answer for this question. Each pie chart represents the percentage of respondents that choose a given option.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu-interim-report/assets/img/charts/CounselingDist.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;!-- &lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src='/kathmandu-interim-report/assets/img/charts/NextSixMonthsChallengesMultiples.png'/&gt;&lt;figcaption class='maincolumn-figure'&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt; --&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2021 05:46:04 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/kathmandu-interim-report/articles/21/workforce-impact</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/kathmandu-interim-report/articles/21/workforce-impact</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>css</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
