<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kathmandu Interim report</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>/kathmandu-interim-report/</link>
    <atom:link href="/kathmandu-interim-report/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 01:45:49 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 01:45:49 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.2.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Lockdown and its economic effects</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In this section, we look at the economic impact that the Covid-19 pandemic has had on the Nepali tourism workforce. Insights shown below have been derived from the responses of 107 participants who took part in the C2M2 Workforce survey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;still-looking-for-jobs&quot;&gt;STILL LOOKING FOR JOBS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Around 90% of our respndents reported losing their job at least once during the pandemic. While a very small proportion of these workers have been successful in gaining employment, a sizable majority are still without jobs and currently looking for economic opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu-interim-report/assets/img/charts/LostJobsSplit.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;Note: The group &amp;#8220;working now&amp;#8221; &lt;strong&gt;also includes&lt;/strong&gt; those who are presently working in sectors other than tourism, but are interested in re-entering the tourism sector.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;pay-cuts-the-new-normal&quot;&gt;PAY CUTS: THE New NORMAL?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even with those lucky few people who have managed to hold on to their jobs (10%, see chart below) throughout the pandemic, living with a pay cut has become a harsh reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu-interim-report/assets/img/charts/StayedEmployedSplit.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;It is worth mentioning at this point that most of our respondents work as trekking and/or mountain guides. This should explain why most were not able to hold on to their jobs, as most guides are hired by tourists. See &lt;a&gt;survey demographics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Around 91% of our respondents reported that earnings haven’t gotten back to pre-covid levels. To make matters worse, 80% of our respondents reported not seeing their earnings return to pre-covid levels for more than a year now (see graph below).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu-interim-report/assets/img/charts/LastDateFullSalaryDist2.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;Note: This charts contains responses from &lt;strong&gt;all&lt;/strong&gt; of our respondents.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It appears the situation is going to get even more difficult with the second wave approaching.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;dealing-with-the-financial-impact&quot;&gt;Dealing with the financial impact&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our survey provides some useful insight to different financial strategies used by our respondents in dealing with this economic shock brought forth by the crisis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;savings-reduced-to-near-zero&quot;&gt;SAVINGS: REDUCED to NEAR-zero&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The indefinite nature of the pandemic has resulted in a situation where many workers (~ 90%) have seen their savings reduced to zero or near-zero levels. This is alarming, especially with the second-wave looming around the corner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu-interim-report/assets/img/charts/SavingsChangeDist.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;selling-assets-household-items-are-the-first-to-go&quot;&gt;SELLING ASSETS: Household items are the first to go&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Around one in every five respondents has had to do away with some of their household assets. Thankfully, only a few of our respondents have had to sell professional equipment (7%) or land and property (7%) so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu-interim-report/assets/img/charts/SoldStuffMultiples.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;borrowing-money-friends-and-family-to-the-rescue&quot;&gt;BORROWING MONEY: Friends and family to the rescue&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our in-person interviews revealed that workers in the tourism sector shy away from borrowing though financial institutions. The reason is that they lack property, real-estate, or other assets that can be provided as collateral. And indeed, our survey results also seem to corroborate with this idea, with nearly three-quarters (75%) of our srespondents admit to borrowing exclusively from friends and family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu-interim-report/assets/img/charts/BorrowingSplit.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The situation is worsened by the fact that at present, nearly all (98%) of our respondents report that they are in some form of debt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu-interim-report/assets/img/charts/LoanExposure.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, it appears being in debt is now part of the new normal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;financial-challenges-in-the-next-six-months&quot;&gt;financial challenges in the next six months&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu-interim-report/assets/img/charts/NextSixMonthsChallengesRnk1Dist.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/kathmandu-interim-report/assets/img/charts/NextSixMonthsChallengesMultiples.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&quot;maincolumn-figure&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2021 05:46:04 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/kathmandu-interim-report/articles/21/economic-impact</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/kathmandu-interim-report/articles/21/economic-impact</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>css</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
